No living creature were hurt during
the production of this show.
Brought to you by historicalfuntv.com
Who did this?
Who?
We saw Rogatus' flag at the scene, my Bey.
- Bring Karayel, Göktuğ.
- Eyvallah(okay), my Bey.
Ambush!
Brothers, they are attacking
Turgut Bey's alps!
We'll deliver his relics to...
Turgut Bey.
Bury the dead.
Dig graves for traitors!
As you order, my Bey.
My Bey.
Karayel.
Go, brothers, go!
Karayel!
Brother!
They raided my home,
slaughtered Karayel!
He was from my blood!
They cut my wings, brother!
Now they are telling us...
"We'll not let you stay here...
... we are after you".
What stops the one who...
...raided our base from raiding
my tent?
The one who slaughtered Karayel...
...can slaughter my Orhan tomorrow!
The top is responsible for...
...an alp's mistake.
Water sleeps but the enemy never sleeps.
You are the leader!
Why were you not awake?
Boran!
My Bey.
- Are the horses ready?
- They're ready, my Bey.
We are going to set off right away.
We'll be at Turgut Bey's tent
before sunrise.
We can't make our martyrs wait.
As you command, my Bey.
You are not coming, brother.
What happened happened.
We have to be sure who did it.
You'll go to Rogatus, to Bilecik.
Invite him to my tent.
We'll look right at his eyes.
We look so that we can see if he did it.
As you command, my Bey.
Turgut Bey Tent.
- Can I come in, my Bey.
- Come, Kutan.
Is there anything about Osman Bey.
No, my Bey.
No one showed up.
They'll come.
They will come.
I hope nothing happ...
They'll come safe and sound Inshallah,
Kutay.
Osman Bey will bring our brothers.
He will.
If he can't...
A proof, just a proof.
A proof of the cruel
who slaughtered Karayel.
Sergeant Ayhan.
My valiant alps!
My Bey, you promised me that my
dad would return!
They not only martyred him,
also cut his fingers!
You promised me!
Damn them all!
They murdered my son!
May Allah curse them!
Osman Bey.
Osman Bey,
in whom all the community trusts.
You couldn't keep your promise.
The Lord tricked you!
Turgut Bey, watch your words!
You are talking to
Ertugrul Ghazi's son Osman Bey.
I kept my promise!
We did right at Kosses issue.
What about my Alps?
What about my fellows?
How did it happen? Tell me Osman Bey.
Who? How?
Vengeance...
...destroys its keeper.
You are the Bey of your tent.
If you burn yourself down...
You'll burn everyone down.
We have nothing to lose, don't you see?
It's time to go all in.
Do not get close to them.
Protect yourself, Osman Bey.
You are being naive.
Don't.
We have to take revenge for
our brothers.
Command us to fight, my Bey!
We'll take revenge.
We'll kill that infidel Kosses.
It's not certain if it's Kosses or not.
There's something else.
Let things settle down...
Wait for things to settle down.
So tell me who that was!
Who was it, Osman Bey?
I said what I had to said.
Your Alps are now martyrs.
They reached the glorious position
we all want to have.
Now live with your pain.
Bury our martyrs.
So, this is all you have to say...
Eyvallah(okay) Osman Bey.
Eyvallah.
Are we going to wait, my Bey?
Bilecik Castle.
To what do I owe this invite, Gündüz Bey?
Do not, just do not pretend you don't
know, Lord Rogatus.
Did you slaughter Turgut Bey's Alps?
What?
What are you talking about,
Gündüz Bey?
You were not alone, Lord.
You were not alone.
Then Turgut Bey's alps...
Now Osman Bey's horse.
I don't get it.
Why would I do such a thing?
Okay.
You'll speak to Osman Bey, not me.
We are waiting for you in our tent
before sunset, Lord
Boran!
Go to Michael Kosses immediately!
Tell him about the ambush.
Let's see if he knows something
about this.
Eyvallah(okay) my Bey.
If his tongue doesn't tell...
his hands will, his eyes will.
Something will definitely tell it.
Observe him well.
Eyvallah my Bey.
So...
you want to become a soldier.
- Is that right?
- Yes sir.
Alright.
Here is a chance for you to
show your skills.
Attack.
What should I do?
Hm?
Should I beg you to attack me?
Or should I cut your empty heads off
your worthless bodies?
What are you looking at?
Attack!
- Speaking in Greek -
Holy war wounds should always be carried
proudly.
Take them away!
I don't want to see them.
Train them until their
skills are observable!
Do not be polite to them!
As wise as he is, as sharp as his sword.
Here is my brother!
You are almighty enough to be
the Emperor of Byzantine.
However, you let Turgut, who is a Bey
of a small tent, abduct me.
I took my sister back at the end, right?
Here you are.
Yes, I am.
But Turgut didn't pay for abducting me.
Do not be sure about that,
my beautiful sister.
Sir.
- I am listening, Nesto.
- Everything goes as you wish.
There's no sign of us.
Moreover, everyone thinks Rogatus
killed Turgut's alps.
You are excellent when it comes to
outsmarting your enemies, again.
Wannabe Bey paid for it by losing his alps.
- What's more?
- You made it look like Rogatus' job.
Your intelligence is stunning.
Here is my brother!
Now we have a bigger problem.
The Emperor wanted me to find Gregor.
I am still empty-handed.
Where do you think he is?
Not at Rogatus.
I am sure about that.
Catalans didn't let them act.
What about Nicola?
Can Priest Gregor be there?
If Nikola had the Priest, he'd
deliver him already.
You are right.
Nikola wouldn't postpone the chance
to win Emperor's favour.
So who has him?
Do you have someone else in mind?
If it's not Rogatus and Nikola...
There's only one person who can do this
around here.
That is Bey of Kayi Osman.
Firstly, I have to be sure.
There's only one way to be sure.
They slaughtered Turgut Bey's alps...
and our Bey's horse.
We have gone through a lot, Hatuns.
Elders say "you must be afraid of the
silent ones."
What did they want from a sinless animal?
They wanted to...
threaten us, Ayse Hatun.
Osman Bey will make them pay for sure!
Mother!
Sit down, daughter.
Of course he will.
He will.
They think they damaged my Osman.
However, my Osman will stand up again.
He will rear up again, Inshallah.
He will rear up, Inshallah.
Inshallah.
His mother is with him now.
Now Hatuns, it's time to get back
to work.
Merchants of Iznik want the famous
rugs of Kayi.
Demand is high and we have little time.
We have to get back to work right away.
Bala Hatun will manage it.
As you all know, she is responsible
of the rughouse.
The floor is yours, Bala.
Hatuns...
...we'll start weaving the rugs
in the morning, Inshallah.
Inshallah.
Gonca, take care of Hatuns.
Don't worry Bala.
Thank you all in advance,
skillful Hatuns of Kayi.
The fame of our rugs is spreading
thanks to your efforts.
- Thank you.
- Thank you Bala Hatun.
Bala Hatun, Hatuns of Kizilcabeyogullari
are good at weaving rugs.
Now that the demand is high
and we have little time...
Hatuns of Kizilcabeyogullari are
ready to help.
They are quick.
Thank you Malhun Hatun.
It's not necessary right now.
Kayi Hatuns overcome.
Right, Hatuns?
Yes, for sure, Inshallah.
Mother Selcan, excuse me.
Of course, daughter.
Ayse Hatun.
Harmanya Castle.
Rogatus Laskaris.
I am not surprised, to be honest!
Only he could perform such treason!
Maybe he wanted to kill you all there...
and lay the blame on me.
I am glad to see you alive.
So are you here to inform me?
No, Lord Kosses.
I am here to ask by my Bey's name.
Do you know anything about this attack?
If I had known...
I would have done everything I could
to prevent this.
Send my condolences to Osman Bey, please.
Catalans...
are full of mercenaries.
If I can go back to my Bey's tent
safe and sound.
I'll surely send your condolences.
Boran Alp.
Don't go alone. Bithnyia is dangerous.
Nesto, prepare a troop to
accompany Boran Alp.
Of course.
Allah-u Akbar
(Allah is the greatest)
My valiant alps!
Have you ever seen Turgut Bey not
taking revenge for his brothers?
Have you seen him letting them down?
Osman Bey...
Bey of Kayi.
He is in politics, obviously.
He can have his own way.
Our way is certain!
Our brothers have been martyred by
the infidel's dirty game.
They are treachers!
We don't even know who they are!
If no one is guilty when we have martyrs,
that means everyone is guilty!
Alps, we are going to take revenge
for our brothers soon.
We are going to attack their caravans
like wolves!
We'll destroy them!
We shall mourn till sunrise.
We shall mourn so that sun rises
for our revenge!
Allah-u Akbar
(Allah is the greatest)
Boran.
Yes my Bey.
Things are unclear.
The only thing I am sure is that
Kosses cut alps' fingers.
Do not go alone.
Take some soldiers with you while leaving
Armankaya.
As you know, things are unclear.
Eyvallah (okay) my Bey.
Don't do it.
Leave us alone.
Have mercy!
My Bey, you promised that my father
would return.
They martyred him,
also they cut his fingers!
You promised.
A finger for a finger.
Now go to your Lord Michael Kosses.
This is for the cut fingers
of Turgut Bey's alps.
If I could have him here...
He would paid for this.
Let's go.
Bala Hatun forgot that we are the
Hatuns of this tent too...
just because we stayed in
for forty days.
It's time to remind the ones who forgot
that we are here.
Gokce...
I wish you to be responsible for this.
Go to Kizilcabey Tent quickly. Bring the
most skillful Hatuns to weave rugs.
As you order, Malhun Hatun.
But...
Selcan Hatun held responsible Bala Hatun
on this job.
Bala Hatun didn't want our Hatun.
How will she react?
It's too late, Gokce.
Bala Hatun can't see things coming.
She won't make it by time.
Also, we are not doing anything wrong.
We want to help.
They reject our help.
Now go fetch the Hatuns.
If we manage to do this job...
we will gain dignity here.
Gokce, I want something else from you.
Leave your two most trusted Hatuns
with my Orhan.
They must stay in the tent all the time.
It's dangerous out here nowadays.
Do not worry.
He says he didn't do it.
He says he knows neither about Alps...
nor about the horse.
What do you think, brother?
How did he react when he saw you?
A part of me says
"it's obvious, it must be Rogatus."
The other part of me says...
I don't know, I am not sure as well,
Osman Bey.
He was like hearing it for the first time
when we talked.
However, he wants Gregor the most.
I don't know.
We'll figure it out, brother.
Once he arrives in our tent...
Once he faces us...
...then we'll understand.
Any trace yet?
No, my bey.
We searched everywhere.
There isn't a single spot that
we didn't check.
But...
no...
but we'll find it.
Inshallah.
Harmankaya Castle
You need to taste this.
It's delicious.
But it's enough for now.
Because I want you to preserve
your hunger until the meat.
You know, not every chief can spread
the meat...
from its bones.
It should be done with dexterity.
Never tore it apart.
Or else it won't be delicious.
Allow me, brother.
Look.
There is a nerve here.
Here is my sister.
She sees what others can't,
and she takes care of it.
You were always like this.
Smart and dangerous.
Osman's envoy.
The bey of the Kayı must
have doubts about you.
I think your plans about Rogatus
isn't going well.
Cooking is like a game
with rules, Mari.
If you don't follow to rules...
your meal won't be tasty.
Yes.
We spread it.
Like I said...
cooking is a matter of patience.
You should believe in your brother.
You know that I always believe in you.
Come on, then. Help me.
So we can begin.
We don't want Aya Nikola to be
left hungry, right?
Of course, we don't.
My lord.
There is something important.
Osman.
He cut our soldiers' fingers.
If he stopped at the fingers...
he's also suspicious of Rogatus.
So, he doesn't think we are responsible.
When you said important, I thought
it was about Father Gregor.
There isn't anything new about
Father Gregor yet, my lord.
Of course not!
Nothing can happen with the likes of you!
Get out!
You, my Karayel,
my companion for life...
you accompanied me
for so many years.
You carried me when I was
young and inexperienced.
You were bled but you ran into
battles without stopping.
I owe you my life.
My noble Karayel, you were
a witness to my joy...
anger, and oaths...
I swear to Allah...
those who ripped off my wings...
Karayel!
those who took you from me...
will be crushed under the shoes of
many noble horses like you.
I take an oath...
I won't let your blood on the ground!
Be my witness, my father...
be my witness, my Allah...
Harmankaya Castle
My dear friend...
when I was equipping my soldiers with
Rogatus's shields to send them to Osman...
you did a great job.
You killed Osman's well-loved horse.
Ripping his head off?
You are really merciless, you know that?
You are a real Turk.
I'm sure when Osman finds out what
happened, he was frustrated.
What do you say?
I've only done the job you asked,
Lord Kosses.
-We did our job.
-You did well, Bahadır.
We increased the number of alps
around the tribe as you want, my bey.
-Keep your eyes open.
-Don't worry, my bey.
Your new job is much more important.
Father Gregor.
I think he's in Osman's hands.
Is there anything that you noticed
in the tribe?
I'm not sure if it's Gregor or not but...
I know that something is being kept
hidden in that tent.
Is that so?
They don't let anyone in but
Osman's loyal alps.
And no one leaves the tent. Nobody
knows what's inside.
You'll find out who is inside
that tent, Bahadır.
My feelings never deceived me.
I feel that we are getting closer
to Gregor.
We are so close, Bahadır.
So close.
Bala Hatun, be careful.
Now you carry two lives.
You need to sit and rest.
Gündüz.
Mother.
Where is Osman?
Isn't he here yet?
What should he do, mother? We let
our brother down.
What should he do?
He wants to stay alone.
Sit.
Welcome.
Are you alright?
With the name of Allah.
Enjoy your meal.
Anything new, brother?
No, Osman Bey.
Alps are still searching. They must've
left a trace.
We'll find it.
Inshallah.
I don't think they can enter when
there are so many alps, my bey.
You are right.
But it wasn't someone from inside.
How did they do it then, mother?
It's not someone from inside but
they can't enter either.
It must be someone who can
enter freely.
We do trade and host guests.
So many people enter and leave.
Thank Allah for today.
We passed many trials and
had many casualties.
But today, we are at this table again.
Thank Allah for gathering us around
this table.
Amin.
-Amin.
I should take a rest.
Enjoy your meal.
Harmankaya Castle
Mari.
If your eyes weren't shining
like a gem...
I was nearly forgetting about
the gift I bought for you.
Glamorous.
I hope you like it.
If you allow me.
I really liked it, Aya Nikola.
Thank you.
I've never met anyone better at
making their friends pleased, Nikola.
I like this gentle act from Aya Nikola,
brother.
But I've never been a woman who is
easy to please.
You know it.
What should I do to please you,
Dear Mari?
Do you know what is the thing that
impressed me the most about you?
I'm curious.
You change the lives of those
who hurt your friends.
Mari, if you want it...
I can change the world even.
-You must know the Turk who kidnapped me--
-Turgut.
Yes, Turgut.
-Will he get away with this--
-He won't.
I promise you, Mari, he won't.
So, I'll start changing the world
from Turgut.
-Nikola.
-Rogatus.
I'm glad you are here too.
There are important matters I want to
talk about.
What a surprise!
-May I enter, my bey?
-Come, mother.
Come.
You were just like this when you were
a child and sad. You would be alone.
And you would understand me and
come to me.
You would cure my motherlessness.
How can I repay you, mother?
What payment between a mother
and a son, son?
I cured your motherlessness and
you cured my grief of losing a child.
We cured each other's wounds.
Get yourself together now.
Does it fit Osman Bey to be like this?
It's heavy, mother.
We've shown weakness.
We couldn't protect what we were
responsible of.
They killed Turgut Bey's alps first.
Then, the enemy sneaked into the
tribe and took my Karayel.
-Isn't this weakness, mother?
-Not at all!
What are you saying, son?
You are too hard on yourself.
Look, son. The mountain's burden
is as heavy as the mountain.
You made all heathens kneel.
They act behind you because
they can't face you.
You will overcome this too.
There is a saying, Allah gives us burdens
as heavy as we can carry.
May Allah give you heavy burdens.
Amin, mother. Amin.
I should leave so you can rest.
After all these words, it's not good
to sit. There is much to do, mother.
Mashallah.
So, Osman accused me of killing
Turgut's alps.
Is there anything you want
to say about this, Kosses.
Osman told me about his suspicion
of you.
I told him how baseless his
suspicion was.
I hope the truth will be revealed soon,
my friend.
Whether you hope or not, I'll reveal it.
Rogatus, you didn't lead
that attack, did you?
You are with friends, you don't need
to hide it.
I'm with friends.
Do you think the same, Kosses?
That I'm with friends?
If you doubt it, don't you think
it's weird to be at our table?
-I can leave if I disturb you--
-Rogatus.
Will we stab each other instead
of building an alliance?
-You are being resentful.
-You are calling me resentful...
while someone is trying to
feed me to Osman, Nikola.
And also, I wasn't
only accused of killing the Alps...
but also killing Osman's horse!
Osman's horse is killed?
That's a pity.
Someone crossed the line, huh?
Whatever, we have more important
problems...
in Bhytinia. I can't mourn for
Osman's horse now.
Father Gregor is still missing.
Are you aware of that?
Where did that man go?
Underground?
He is a priest, Nikola.
Maybe he ascended.
Father Gregor...
is a respectable reverend.
I assume the emperor
doesn't have the same feelings.
I said it before. I don't think anyone
here has Father Gregor. I'm sure of it.
But Osman...
I'm not sure.
I'm not sure who has him.
But I agree with you about
none of us having him, Nikola.
What do you think, Dear Rogatus?
In Bhytinia...
we can't be sure of anyone
or anything.
That's the only thing I think of.
It was delicious.
Unfortunately, I have to go.
Until next time.
Master Gregor, we must take it
out of your arm at once.
-Your wound is getting worse.
-Not before escaping, Andreas.
We can't take it before assuring
our security.
We don't know when this captivity
will end, Master Gregor.
It looks like we'll stay
here for a while.
Osman has alps everywhere.
-We can't inform Rogatus.
-You are mistaken, Andreas.
Osman is a smart man.
He didn't kidnap us to hide us.
He knows the emperor's politics...
and the weaknesses of Byzantine.
-He must've planned his moves.
That's why he kidnapped us.
He wants to work up the fight between
the Catholics and the Orthodoxes.
So, keeping us here won't benefit him.
Osman's politics will take us to Rogatus,
Andreas.
Osman Bey, it's time.
It's getting dark.
Rogatus isn't coming.
We know our enemy now, huh?
You are right.
By not attending to our invitation,
Rogatus gets suspicious.
If he isn't coming, we'll go to him.
Then, we'll understand if
it's fear...
or guiltyness.
-Then, if you allow me.
Wait, brother.
Tell me, my bey.
Will you judge me?
It's not the day for judgement.
It's the day for unity.
I don't want to ride alone.
Redemption of mistakes is possible
by unity, right, my bey?
Indeed.
-Aya Nikola is tasteful.
-He is.
But he is ready to fall into
a trap, like all men.
You should've seen him looking
into my eyes.
I'm sure he fell in love with
you at first sight.
It was so obvious.
I can't even imagine what he'll
do to Turgut for kidnapping me.
My lady...
-I want to ask you if you allow me.
-Of course, ask away.
But wait! You wonder what I want
from Nikola, right?
What I want from the others.
His power.
I'll play with him for a while.
Then I'll move him like a puppet.
A puppet that will do whatever I want.
You may leave.
Poor Turgut.
You'll pay the price for kidnapping me,
just like your alps.
-Any news from Rogatus?
-No, brother.
Then, we'll go.
Alps!
Kosses.
He wouldn't come without telling.
It must be important.
He must've come here for his
soldiers' fingers.
Clear the way!
Kosses' soldiers are here, my bey.
Where is Lord Kosses?
Why did he send you here?
Haven't you heard? Are you deaf
or mute?
Rogatus?
You invited me and I'm here.
Why are you surprised, Osman Bey?
Turn to your jobs, women.
Come on.
What's happening here?
-Who are you, women?
-Kızılcabeyoğlu's women, Gonca Hatun.
-They are here for work.
-What are you saying, Gökçe?
Look at me, woman!
You are stepping over your limit.
Bala Hatun didn't allow this. How can
you bring them here?
It's Malhun Hatun's orders,
not mine.
-Speak to her.
-Bala Hatun makes the decisions.
She is in charge of here!
She answered Malhun Hatun's
question as you heard.
Now, tell the women to return
to their tribe.
The workers are behind me.
Gonca Hatun.
Gökçe and the women are here
by my order.
Speak to me if you have objections.
-Give me patience...
-Power to your elbows, women.
Make me proud.
What's wrong, Gonca? Why are you
waiting here like this?
Malhun Hatun brought women from her
tribe to work here.
And put Gökçe in charge.
What should we do now, Bala Hatun?
Bilecik is known by its workmen,
Osman Bey.
They can make the same shields that
Harmankaya soldiers hold.
That's the kind of trap Kosses
made for you. Don't fall for it.
If I had ordered my soldiers
to attack your tribe...
wouldn't you think that it was Kosses?
I wouldn't, Rogatus.
But there is no need for such
exhibitions.
If I was sure of your treachery...
you wouldn't be here talking to me.
What about Gündüz Bey's invitation?
I thought you were deceived
by Kosses.
Despite all our trade and friendship--
I'm Ertuğrul Ghazi's son, Osman Bey.
I know well about your schemes.
But the truth has a tendency...
to get revealed sooner or later.
Sheik Edebali wanted to
send the workers of your tribe...
to learn mining at my
silver mines, and I accept it.
I'm providing many goods from you,
instead of buying them cheaper.
These are not hostile attitudes,
Osman Bey.
And I want the truth to be revealed
as much as you do.
Until next time.
Everything got more complicated, brother.
Indeed, brother.
Indeed.
But, we know one thing...
all traces are leading to
the same direction.
Whoever wants Gregor is doing this.
You are right, Osman.
Kosses, Nikola, Rogatus and
even the Emperor.
They all want the priest.
Don't worry.
-We'll increase the caution.
-No.
The opposite, brother.
We'll take Priest Gregor
out of the tribe.
Whoever wants him will use
this opportunity.
Then, we'll know who is the enemy.
Inshallah, Osman Bey.
Inshallah.
Now, let's take the good news
to Priest Gregor.
Malhun Hatun, good day.
Thank you, Bala Hatun.
Malhun Hatun, haven't we
talked about this?
Haven't I told you that there is no need?
What is this?
You are right, Bala Hatun.
We have.
But you forget one thing. I'm also
a Hatun of this tribe.
I don't need orders to
do something.
Of course, you are a Hatun of
this tribe.
But I'm the Head Hatun of this tribe.
When everyone does as they wish,
there can be no unity.
The tribe has an order.
Bala Hatun, you are forgetting
another thing.
I'm a bey's daughter.
I have no lessons to take from you
about administration.
My intentions are sincere. There is
little time. We want to help.
This much job can't be done with
Kayı' women only.
Come on, women. Get to your
job.
-Our carpets are on your hands now.
-Thank you, Bala Hatun.
Ahmet.
May Allah give strength to your elbows.
May Allah help you.
-May your job be finished in no time.
-Thank you, Ahmet.
So, the Kayı's most overhasty alp
wished you his best.
-Inshallah it'll be finished soon.
-Inshallah.
Kill our enemies for the sake of
your love.
Destroy all our enemies because
we are your followers.
Our God Jesus Christ,
save us with your mercy.
Amen.
-Finish your prayer. Don't mind us.
-We don't. It was finished.
I say that, Priest Gregor...
you will do your worships in the church
in Söğüt, freely.
Don't be surprised.
Our Prophet, praise be upon him,
used to do that.
No non-muslim would get hurt...
or be disturbed during their prayers,
under his rule.
-I follow his way.
-Are you doing that by keeping us captive?
You aren't captives here.
You are our guests.
We keep you here to protect
your lives.
I care about your worship as much
as...
I care about my Christian people at Söğüt.
My Alps will take you to Söğüt.
-Göktuğ, Saltuk.
-My bey.
-You will take Priest Gregor.
-Alright, my bey.
-Master Gregor.
-Yes, Andreas.
This is a great opportunity
to reach Rogatus.
You'll go with this cart.
But be cautious. No one will see
the priest entering the church.
Make sure that he is alone there.
Mashallah. Which one do you think
will be my bey's wind, Master Davud?
The horses don't have the wind, Ahmed.
Osman Bey does.
Ahmed.
-Tell me, Smith.
-My bey...
this pretty one's all ancestors are known.
It's quick and strong.
My bey, They say that one of his
ancestors was a Turkmen horse.
And it shows. He is noble and smart.
He understands every word
you speak.
Inshallah he won't make you miss
Karayel.
And this is Michael Kosses of Harmankaya's
gift...
for your son. An Andalusian horse.
This belongs to Orhan. It should wait
for Orhan.
It should wait for Orhan.
My bey.
This beauty speaks.
Allah created humans from earth
and horses from the wind.
It wants to accompany you.
It says that being horseless is
for the Dervishes.
A bey needs a horse. If he lets me...
I want to be his wings!
You say so, Kumral Abdal?
-Master Davud.
-My bey?
Saddle the horse up. I have an important
job to do.
-I want to go with my new companion.
-As you order, my bey.
Old man, go.
You can continue later.
I just cleaned here.
I'll take care of it.
Old man, go.
We can take care of here.
Come on.
You did great, Andreas.
Now we wait for the
letter to reach there.
I wish Umur Bey was here.
He would want to see the 40th
day of his grandson.
Do you think Umur Bey is there
by now, Bahadır?
He must be at Karbala. He'll reach
Kaaba soon. He is healthy, inshallah.
Amin, Bahadır.
Amin.
Do as Umur Bey would want.
Do as Osman Bey says.
Be at ease, Malhun Hatun.
Who can say that Turgut Bey
doesn't avenge his brothers?
-That he left their blood on the ground?
-Allahu Akbar!
For the blood of our brothers.
For the weeping children
they left behind.
Ambush!
Charge!
Yes. I'm listening.
Lord Rogatus.
Father Gregor...
He gave me this to bring
it to you.
I'm in the hands of the devil.
At Osman Bey of the Kayı.
-Who are you?
-My name is Lune.
I'm a friend of Father Gregor's,
from Constantinople to this day.
I was in reclusion at the church in Söğüt.
-He found me.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
You may leave.
Osman...
Lord Kosses. As you ordered, I watched
the tribe without blinking an eye.
-And?
-They took two people out.
But I couldn't recognize their faces.
They secretely took them to Söğüt.
You did well, Bahadır.
And they are still at Söğüt.
The traitor will attack us to take
the priest.
They'll wait for our weakest moment.
Some of the alps will be around
the cart.
The rest will come with me to strike
the real blow.
When they think they have the priest,
we'll strike them.
As you order, my bey.
Ambush!
Turgut Bey!
Where is your Bey?
Come here!
I want Turgut alive.
He's my gift.
As I will give him to Mari.
Turgut Bey! Where is he?
Where is the Bey of this tent?
Alps! Protect the priest.
- Protect the priest.
- Don't let the priest go.
Attack!
Stay away.
Allah is eternal!
Take the priest.
It's a trap!
Göktuğ!
Don't let them run away.
You know what to do.
Don't worry.
Oh God.
Come on.
I caught this dog.
Take him to the tent and make him talk.
Then we'll know whom he's loyal to.
-Your command, my Bey.
- Alps.
What is happening?
My Bey.
Aygül and Başsungur will take the
priest from another way.
Göktuğ, Saltuk.
You will stay behind the carriage.
- Your command, my Bey.
Other valiants will
replace with the priest.
Come on, Alps.
Get off.
However, they won't suspect Rogatus.
Catalans attacked Rogatus' soldiers in
İznik, to abduct the priest.
Okay, Rogatus didn't send these dogs.
Then who did?
Nikola? Kosses?
- Or the emperor
- All of them may be.
All.
Firstly he should talk.
Then we'll know.
Okay.
Alps. We're going to the tent.
Where is Turgut Bey?
Where is your Bey?
They don't know where he is.
You tell me.
Where is your Turgut Bey?
You're late, Turgut Bey.
You're too late.
Isn't he late?
Yes.
Nikola.
Ignoble dog!
Turgut Bey.
Now you...
and your men drop your swords...
if you don't want anyone to hurt.
Now...
Now.
Alps!
I don't need a sword to kill you.
I will kill you slowly with my hands.
Slowly.
You're late, Turgut Bey.
Too late.
- I came before you, it's mine.
- I came before you, Hatun.
I did.
Hatun!
Don't take what is mine!
What is going on, Hatuns?
What are you doing?
- Is this because of just a string?
- Enough, Hatuns!
They are always looking at us!
Tell me, Gonca Hatun.
Why are they here?
- Are you against Malhun Hatun's orders?
- Hatun! Get yourself together!
- What do you think you're doing?
- Gonca! Gökçe!
Get off of each other!
Don't you hear me?
What are you doing?
A Kayı Hatun shouldn't behave like that.
Mother Hayme wouldn't!
Tell me, Hatuns!
From now on, we are one!
We are one!
We are on the same side with
Kızılcabeyoğlu Tent.
This is it.
Don't behave badly.
Come on.
Malhun Hatun did some things obviously.
We should figure it out
before my Osman hears it.
Bring the Hatuns.
You don't talk, don't you?
Okay.
Boran!
You come here every year.
You know we're mercenaries, Osman Bey.
Like people who don't
have anything to fight for.
Catalonia, Al-Andalus...
Do you know our country?
No.
I know some ways to there.
After France...
Why are you coming here?
When Muslims came to Al-Andalus...
they didn't have permission from us.
Are you still fighting with
Muslims in Al-Andalus?
No.
They are not strong enough to fight.
We'll erase Emirate of Granada
from history sooner or later.
They are not Turk, they are Arab.
If they believe in Allah, they
are all one.
Us in one part, you in another one.
Have you ever fought Turks before?
I have fought so many pirate Turks in the
Mediterranean.
I have.
The Franks are not good
at wars as you are.
The Turk sailors in the Mediterranean...
who are they?
Do you remember them?
They are from...
Karaman.
They said they come from Karaman land.
Yes.
Karamanoğulları. (Karamanids)
They are Turks.
What happened...
- when you fought?
- As I said...
They were good at wars.
Mikhael Kosses, the Lord of Harmankaya...
and his sister came.
- Make him talk.
- Yes, my Bey.
Don't kill him.
He should talk.
Your command, my Bey.
Do they live here?
How can a person live here?
It smells.
It's surprising but true.
They can affect anyone.
For now.
- Welcome, Lord Kosses.
- Thank you, Osman Bey.
Do you accept uninvited guests?
We do.
Come to my tent.
With pleasure.
I didn't like what happened today.
What I saw didn't suit you Hatuns.
You all know that.
As I said.
Head Hatun of this tent is...
Bala Hatun.
Don't forget that.
Behave well.
Bala Hatun, Osman Bey is summoning you.
If you let me.
I wanted to thank you when I heard that my
brother will visit you.
Thank you. You saved me
from that barbaric man.
Turgut Bey is not someone
you think he is.
On the contrary, he is a good Turkmen Bey.
- Can I come in, my Bey?
- Come in.
Bala Hatun.
Bala Hatun is my wife.
Mikhal Kosses...
and his sister Mari.
Welcome.
Take care of our guest, Bala.
Come. Let me show you around the tent.
Tell me, Mikhael Kosses.
Are you here to ask for your
soldiers' fingers?
Of course no.
I won't fall out with you because of some
soldiers who lost their fingers.
They wouldn't be
trapped if they were good soldiers.
Boran.
He mentioned to me that Rogatus
tried to attack you.
Yes, Kosses.
Yes.
Rogatus' offensive behavior
deranges Bithynia.
He's not someone to support.
You should know that I stand by you.
I didn't like it.
As proportion matters.
Right?
Turgut Bey should look...
the same both parts, with my punches.
Enough.
Yes.
Harmony.
I like harmony.
What did you think, Turgut Bey?
Did you think you would live in peace
after what you did to Mari?
Did you?
- Kill me.
- What?
Kill me.
However, it would be easy.
Right?
Do you know why I treat you well?
You will be a gift to someone I like.
That's why.
Kill me.
Or else, you will regret it.
Enough!
Enough.
Come on.
Brother.
I beat him.
He will talk.
Thanks to my punches.
Come on, talk.
Stop.
Talk! Who is it?
Who is it?
- What? Who?
- Mikhael Kosses.
Osman is the devil.
I am surprised by it.
His plan...
is perfect.
So...
is it impossible...
to run away from his trap?
What about our trap?
How is it going?
Does it work?
It does.
You know what, Lord Rogatus?
You're more generous than Kosses.
If everything works well...
I'll be more generous.
Don't worry.
As we talked.
You will be taken captured.
They will think they have captured you.
They will torture you.
You won't talk.
If you talk instantly, it
will be suspicious. You'll resist.
And then...
you will say that it's Kosses.
Don't worry. I will even
deceive the devil.
Come on.
Even if we couldn't have Priest Gregor...
Kosses will be trapped by his own trap.
He won't even know it.
Osman will find the guilty one.
Bithynia suffered a lot, Osman Bey.
I want ultimate peace.
Can I come in, my Bey?
Come in, Boran.
The Catalan man talked.
The person whom they took orders
from is Mikhael Kosses.
Brought to you by historicalfuntv.com